Guide to the Warren G. Waterman, Class of 1892, Yale College, Photograph Album Documenting Life at Yale
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Warren G. Waterman, Class of 1892, Yale College, photograph album documenting life at Yale
1892-1892
RU 654
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
(1 box)
The collection consists of a photograph album titled "A Pictorial Record of the Class of 1892 in Yale College." The album contains photographs of various student activities, classmates, campus scenes, and aspects of student life at Yale in the 1890s. The album belonged to Warren Gookin Waterman (Yale 1892).
Waterman, Warren Gookin, 1872-1952
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 48-A (YRG 48-A), Yale pictorial records and collections.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
Arranged by topic.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of a photograph album titled "A Pictorial Record of the Class of 1892 in Yale College." The album contains photographs of various student activities, classmates, campus scenes, and aspects of student life at Yale in the 1890s. The album belonged to Warren Gookin Waterman (Yale 1892).
New Haven (Conn.) -- Pictorial works; Photographs; Waterman, Warren Gookin, 1872-1952; Yale College (1887- ). Class of 1892 -- Portraits; Yale University -- Pictorial works; Yale University -- Societies, etc.; Yale University -- Sports; Yale University -- Students
- Photographs, circa 1889-1892; Series I
  - "A pictorial record of the Class of 1892 in Yale College"
    - Outside railroad station (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Southeast corner of the Green (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - East side of the Green (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - College buildings across the Green (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Temple Street crossing the Green (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Welch Hall from the Green (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Old State House - formerly on the Green (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Old Fence - corner of Chapel and College Streets (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Osborne Hall - on site of Old Fence (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - North on Chapel Street from College Street (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - South on Chapel Street (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Dormitories along College Street, north of the Green (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - College Street west from Elm Street (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - College Street toward Sheffield (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Wall Street (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - College Street in winter (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Athenaeum (or Lyceum) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - South side of Old Brick Row to west (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - South side of Old Brick Row to east (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Campus looking west with Old Treasury and Cabinet (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Art School (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Campus toward Battell (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Library (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Old Library (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Dwight Hall (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Campus in winter - east end (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Interior of Battell (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Interior of Old Library (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Memorial Window in Chittenden (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Reading Room in Dwight Hall (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Assembly Room in Dwight Hall (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Class Prayer-meeting room in Dwight (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Stairway in Osborne Hall (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Recitation Room - Old Brick Row (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Cast Room in Art School (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Battell Chapel from Elm Street in winter (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Peabody Museum (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - New Gymnasium (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Kent Laboratory, Sloane Laboratory, Old Gymnasium (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Skull and Bones (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Scroll and Key (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Wolf's Head (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Delta Kappa Epsilon (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Interior of Armory, decorated for Junior Prom (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Freshman class picture on steps of Ken [Chemical Laboratory], 1889 Spring (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - 149 Farnam - four view of interior (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - G. Girty in 149 Farnam (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - O. Bronson and D.T. Huntington in cap & gown (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Room in Brick Row (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - R. Colton in his room (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Five groups on fence, including Luce, Galloway, Husted, S. Webster, Hollister, Manson, Kitchel, Wright and H. McCormick (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Seven groups including Junior Prom Committee, S. Webster in "rooster" pose, McClung drilling Webster, Bayne calling up to a friend (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Glee Club (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Delta Kappa Epsilon group (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Delta Kappa Epsilon players in costume (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Glee Club on tour (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Coming out of Chapel (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Going to exam in Alumni Hall (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Waiting outside Alumni Hall (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Class coming out of Kent [Chemical Laboratory] (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Sophomores with silk hats on Washington's Birthday (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Seniors spinning tops (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Silliman statue overthrown (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Circus Parade passing Osborne Hall (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Eating Club (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Group including Holden, Luce, Marsh (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Group featuring Bill Wright (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Group with organ-grinder - W.G.W. holding camera (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Class picture - on steps of Osborne Hall, 1892 Spring (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Varsity football team - 1891 champions (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Football team (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Handsome Dan (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Morrison and Heffelfinger (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Heffelfinger and McClung (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Morrison, Barber, Heffelfinger (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - McClung (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Bus going to Yale Field (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Scrimmages (football) (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Picture trophy for members of football team (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Yale-Harvard football at Springfield - with flying wedge (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Poster of Yale-Princeton football game (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Track team (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Practicing starts (track) (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Pole-vaulting (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Tennis (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Ollie Campbell (tennis) (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Baseball team (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Yale Field - Princeton baseball (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Stagg at bat (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Class of 1892 baseball team (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Rowing on Lake Whitney (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Poster - "Yale '94 vs Yale '95" (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Crew on river (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Varsity crew (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Class of 1892 Crew (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Durfee Hall at night (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Trunks in basement of Farnam Hall (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Doorway of 149 Farnam (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Window of 149 Farnam from outside (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - [Class of 1892] drilling on campus (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Senior baseball on campus (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Newsboys (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Waiting in line for baseball tickets (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Tent for Commencement luncheon (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Prexie coming out of Chapel (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - W.R. Harper and daughter outside Divinity (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Professor Duncan (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Hotchkiss (Superintendent of Grounds) (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Janitor (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Furniture sale signs (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - outside Old Brick Row - two unidentified men (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Lieutenant Totten (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - "Pop Smith" - mascot (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Joe the Postman (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Cabman (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Willabe Haskell on the dog-trot (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Sandwich man (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Campus cleaner (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Newsboy (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Orange Street (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - East Haven (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Old Foundation beyond East Haven (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - View from room at 84 Wall Street (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Winter on the Green from 149 Farnam Hall (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Summer on the Green from 149 Farnam Hall (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Hillhouse Avenue (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - East Rock (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Whitney Avenue (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - West Rock (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Observatory (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Triangular Park near York Street (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Lake Whitney (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Hopkins Grammar School (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - West Chapel Street (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Elm Street and New Gym (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Skating on Lake Whitney (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Class histories on Class Day (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Football practice and action - five snapshots (Box 1, Folder 51)